<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Data Science Portfolio on Henry Truong</title>
    <link>https://tmhuy0510.github.io/Henry_DS_Portfolio/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Data Science Portfolio on Henry Truong</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 22 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://tmhuy0510.github.io/Henry_DS_Portfolio/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>TidyTuesday: UFC History</title>
      <link>https://tmhuy0510.github.io/Henry_DS_Portfolio/post/ufc-history/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tmhuy0510.github.io/Henry_DS_Portfolio/post/ufc-history/</guid>
      <description>This work is inspired and instructed by Andrew Couch. I would like to express my deepest appreciation to him. The topic is about UFC Match History. The data can be accessed via this link.
The work focuses on cleaning data, performing exploratory analysis, building and tweaking a model and further performing exploratory analysis. Codes used for this work can be found in my github.
There are 3 main questions will be answered:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TidyTuesday: Chocolate Ratings</title>
      <link>https://tmhuy0510.github.io/Henry_DS_Portfolio/post/chocolate-ratings/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tmhuy0510.github.io/Henry_DS_Portfolio/post/chocolate-ratings/</guid>
      <description>This work is inspired by R Data Science: Tidy Tuesday. This week’s topic is about Chocolate Ratings. The data can be accessed via this link.
The work will answer three main questions related to:
 How each continent in the world contribute to the origin of chocolate What words and how they are used describe the chocolate taste Whether we can build a predictive models using text data along with other features to predict chocolate ratings    The work walks through all the steps of a typical data science project, which include:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>R Project: Predictive Text Model</title>
      <link>https://tmhuy0510.github.io/Henry_DS_Portfolio/post/text-predictions/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tmhuy0510.github.io/Henry_DS_Portfolio/post/text-predictions/</guid>
      <description>This topic of this project is to develop a data product predicting the next word when users are texting on their smartphone keyboard. The database used to train the model can be accessed via this link. The database is comprised of 4 sub-databases, each of which corresponds to each language. In this project, the focus is on the English sub-database. The text data within the English sub-database are collected from 3 different types of media:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TidyTuesday: Tuskegee Airmen</title>
      <link>https://tmhuy0510.github.io/Henry_DS_Portfolio/post/tuskegee-airmen/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tmhuy0510.github.io/Henry_DS_Portfolio/post/tuskegee-airmen/</guid>
      <description>This work is inspired by R Data Science: Tidy Tuesday. This week&amp;rsquo;s topic is about Tuskegee Airmen. The data can be accessed via this link.
The work will answer two questions related to:
 Spatial distribution of airmen across the US Correlation between the graduation rank and the type of pilot    The work walks through all the steps of a typical data science project, which include:
 Getting the Data Understanding the Data Cleaning and Wrangling the Data Performing Exploratory Data Analysis Testing Hypothesis and Performing Statistical Inference  The source code can be found in my GitHub.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>R Project: Traffic Collisions in Halifax Regional Municipality</title>
      <link>https://tmhuy0510.github.io/Henry_DS_Portfolio/post/traffic-collisions/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tmhuy0510.github.io/Henry_DS_Portfolio/post/traffic-collisions/</guid>
      <description>This topic of this project is on traffic collisions in Halifax Regional Municipality (HRM) over the period of 2018-2021. The project will find out the tendency of traffic accidents in terms of time, space as well as characteristics related to collisions, roads and drivers. In addition, the project will perform hypothesis testing to make inference from the data of HRM. Lastly, a predictive model will be built to make a prediction on the number of daily incidents occurring in HRM.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Python Project: Athletes and Results of 120 Years of Olympic History</title>
      <link>https://tmhuy0510.github.io/Henry_DS_Portfolio/post/olympics-events/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tmhuy0510.github.io/Henry_DS_Portfolio/post/olympics-events/</guid>
      <description>The purpose of this project is to understand and examine the dataset on Athletes and Results of 120 Years of Olympic History using the data analysis approach. A large part of tools applied in this study include Python and SQL to get and clean the data, to make queries to extract a certain piece of information of interest, to perform exploratory data analysis and to create visualization of the extracted data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>R Project: Languages in Canada in 2016</title>
      <link>https://tmhuy0510.github.io/Henry_DS_Portfolio/post/canadian-languages/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tmhuy0510.github.io/Henry_DS_Portfolio/post/canadian-languages/</guid>
      <description>This topic of this project is to develop a data product using the data set related to languages spoken by Canadian residents. This data set was collected during the 2016 Canadian census. The result of the project is an application used to visualize the answers of the following 2 questions:
 What are the top 3-10 languages of the selected category spoken most as mother tongue? What is the number of people speaking a language at work, given the number of them speaking it at home?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>https://tmhuy0510.github.io/Henry_DS_Portfolio/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tmhuy0510.github.io/Henry_DS_Portfolio/contact/</guid>
      <description>Follow and contact me on these social media platforms.
   Platform URL     Gmail: tmhuy0510@gmail.com   Outlook: henrytruong95@outlook.com   LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/henry-truong-tmh   GitHub: https://github.com/tmhuy0510    </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>