<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>TidyTuesday on Henry Truong</title>
    <link>https://tmhuy0510.github.io/Henry_DS_Portfolio/tags/tidytuesday/</link>
    <description>Recent content in TidyTuesday on Henry Truong</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 22 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://tmhuy0510.github.io/Henry_DS_Portfolio/tags/tidytuesday/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>TidyTuesday: UFC History</title>
      <link>https://tmhuy0510.github.io/Henry_DS_Portfolio/post/ufc-history/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tmhuy0510.github.io/Henry_DS_Portfolio/post/ufc-history/</guid>
      <description>This work is inspired and instructed by Andrew Couch. I would like to express my deepest appreciation to him. The topic is about UFC Match History. The data can be accessed via this link.
The work focuses on cleaning data, performing exploratory analysis, building and tweaking a model and further performing exploratory analysis. Codes used for this work can be found in my github.
There are 3 main questions will be answered:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TidyTuesday: Chocolate Ratings</title>
      <link>https://tmhuy0510.github.io/Henry_DS_Portfolio/post/chocolate-ratings/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tmhuy0510.github.io/Henry_DS_Portfolio/post/chocolate-ratings/</guid>
      <description>This work is inspired by R Data Science: Tidy Tuesday. This week’s topic is about Chocolate Ratings. The data can be accessed via this link.
The work will answer three main questions related to:
 How each continent in the world contribute to the origin of chocolate What words and how they are used describe the chocolate taste Whether we can build a predictive models using text data along with other features to predict chocolate ratings    The work walks through all the steps of a typical data science project, which include:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TidyTuesday: Tuskegee Airmen</title>
      <link>https://tmhuy0510.github.io/Henry_DS_Portfolio/post/tuskegee-airmen/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tmhuy0510.github.io/Henry_DS_Portfolio/post/tuskegee-airmen/</guid>
      <description>This work is inspired by R Data Science: Tidy Tuesday. This week&amp;rsquo;s topic is about Tuskegee Airmen. The data can be accessed via this link.
The work will answer two questions related to:
 Spatial distribution of airmen across the US Correlation between the graduation rank and the type of pilot    The work walks through all the steps of a typical data science project, which include:
 Getting the Data Understanding the Data Cleaning and Wrangling the Data Performing Exploratory Data Analysis Testing Hypothesis and Performing Statistical Inference  The source code can be found in my GitHub.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>